Guide to the Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
American Bureau for Medical Aid to China Records,
1937-1979.
American Bureau for Medical Aid to China.
50 linear ft (ca. 51,350 items in 109 boxes; 5 scrapbooks; 5 oversize folders; 1 oversize photograph album; 43 phonograph tapes; and 5 audio tapes.
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079642
History
ABMAC was founded in 1937 to give aid to Chinese medical and public health services by working through existing Chinese medical agencies. Between 1937 and 1945 more than ten million dollars in aid was given to China. After World War II, ABMAC concentrated on aiding six national medical colleges by administering a fellowship program for faculty members of these colleges to spend a year of study in the United States, by sending American medical faculty members to the six colleges as visiting professors, and by providing technical assistance in the form of books for medical libraries, text books for the classroom, equipment for laboratories and other educational materials. In 1949 when the Peoples Republic of China was established, ABMAC shifted its aid to Taiwan.
Scope and Content
Papers of the American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, Inc., consisting of correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, committee files, membership records, financial records, fund raising records, motion pictures, audio tapes, phonograph records, photographs, posters, publications of ABMAC and other printed materials. Also included are the files of related Chinese relief organizations: Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, 1954-1969; American Emergency Relief, 1941-1946; United Services to China, 1941-1977. Of particular interest are approximately 6,000 photographs of Chinese medical colleges, hospitals, laboratories and personnel and 45 phonograph records including speeches by such ABMAC supporters as Mme. Chiang Kai-Shek, Pearl S. Buck, Wendell Willkie, Fiorello LaGuardia and a number of movie stars.
Subjects
United China Relief (U.S.); American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Chiang Kai-shek.; China--Social conditions.; China--Social life and customs.; China--Health and hygiene.; Public health--International cooperation.; Medical assistance--China.; Medical education--China.; Medical sciences--China.; Medicine--China.; Public health--China.; Agenda.; Albums.; Annual reports.; Bank statements.; Biographies.; Bulletins.; Bylaws.; Contracts.; Drawings.; Financial records.; Interviews.; Legal documents.; Minutes.; Motion pictures.; Newsletters.; Phonodiscs.; Photographs.; Posters.; Press releases.; Reports.; Scrapbooks.; Songs.; Speeches.; Tape recordings.
Acquisition
1980 M-1980 ABMAC and John Watt Gift
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letters are on microfilm.
Boxes 1-3 are on microfilm.
Gift of ABMAC, 1980; gift of John Watt, 1985-1986.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Buck, Pearl Sydenstricker
  - Chennault, Claire Lee
  - Chiang, Mayling Soong (Mme. Chiang Kai-Shek)
  - Hu, Shih
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr. (1887-1944)
  - Root, Walter Stanton
- Series II: Permanent File
  - A (Box 1)
  - Agnew, R. Gordon (Box 1)
  - All India Institute of Hygiene (Box 1)
  - Allen, Vivian B, Foundation (Box 1)
  - ABMAC 10th Anniversary (Box 1)
  - ABMAC China Committee (Box 1)
  - ABMAC Honorary Officers, Staff, etc. (Box 1)
  - ABMAC Miscellaneous Data (Box 1)
  - American Federation of Soroptimist Clubs (Box 1)
  - American Overseas Aid - United Nations Appeal for Children (Box 1)
  - American Red Cross (Box 1)
  - Amigen Project (Box 1)
  - Annual Meeting (1949) - Special Invitations (Box 1)
  - Anonymous: Donor's Fund (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Dr. George E., (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - China. Army: (Box 2)
    - Emergency Medical Service Training School (Box 2)
    - General Medical (Box 2)
    - Army Medical Administration: (Box 2)
    - Army Nursing School (Box 2)
    - Hsu His-lin (Box 2)
    - Lim., Robert - Directorate, of Medical Service (Box 2)
    - Lim, Robert - Reports, (3 Folders) (Box 2)
    - Loo Chih-tea (Box 2)
  - Army Medical College (Box 2)
  - Arnold, Elisabeth (Box 2)
  - Art Asia, Inc. (Box 2)
  - B (Box 3)
  - Bachman, George W., 1942 & 1943, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Background - History (Box 3)
  - Barr, David P. (Box 3)
  - Beeby, Nell V. (Box 3)
  - Editor of American Journal of Nursing (Box 3)
  - Bennett, Ivan L. (Box 3)
  - Berzin, Walter B. (Box 3)
  - Biographies (Box 3)
  - Biographies of Chinese Leaders (Box 3)
  - Blood Bank, 1944 & 1949 (Box 4)
  - Blood Bank - Yi. Chien-lung (Box 4)
  - Blood Bank and Pyrogen – Free Report (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bordley, James, 3rd (Box 4)
  - Bowery Savings Bank (Box 4)
  - Bowl of Rice (Box 4)
  - Bulletins (Box 4)
  - Bowl of Rice (Box 4)
  - Form Letters (Box 4)
  - Bowl of Rice Parties (Box 4)
  - Brodie, Donald (Box 4)
  - Brook Foundation (Box 4)
  - Buck, Pearl (Box 4)
  - Bulletins (Box 4)
  - C (Box 4)
  - Cadwalader, Wickersham and Taft (Box 4)
  - California, Los Angeles (Box 5)
  - California, State of (Box 5)
  - Caltex Petroleum Corporation (Box 5)
  - Certificate of Incorporation (Box 5)
  - Chambelian, Berger and Co. (Box 5)
  - Chase National Bank (Box 5)
  - Chen, K. K. (Box 5)
  - Cheng Pao-nan (Box 5)
  - Chennault, Claire, L. (Box 5)
  - Chennault Fund for Front Line Freedom Fighters (Box 5)
  - Chi Pao-san (Box 5)
  - Chiang Kai-shek, Mme. (Box 5)
  - China Advisory Committee (Box 5)
  - China Defense League (Box 5)
  - China Emergency Relief Committee (Box 5)
  - Minutes and Legal documents (Box 5)
  - China Medical Board of New York, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Chinese Cultural Theater Group6 (Box 6)
  - Chinese Embassy6 (Box 6)
  - Chinese Mass Education Movement (Box 6)
  - Christmas Card Originals (Box 6)
  - Clark and Keating Corp.6 (Box 6)
  - Clise, James W. (Box 6)
  - Commission on Medical Education - T.Y. Tai (Box 6)
  - Committees:
    - Administrative Advisory Committee (June-November 1946) (Box 6)
    - Administrative Committee (1948) (Box 6)
    - Army Medical Seryice and Army Medical Administration (1943-46) (Box 6)
    - Budget Sub-Committee (1943-45) (Box 6)
    - China (Box 6)
    - China Program Committee Chinese Advisory (1943-46) (Box 6)
    - Committee on Commerce and Industry, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
    - Dental Committee Committees (Box 6)
    - Executive (Box 6)
    - Fund Raising (Box 6)
    - General Investment Planning (Box 6)
    - Joint Fund Raising (Box 6)
    - Liaison (Box 6)
    - Library (Box 6)
  - Committees: (Box 7)
    - Medical (1941-46) (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous -, (2 Folders) (Box 7)
    - National Health Administration on (Box 7)
    - National Medical Colleges and Sub-Committee on Medical Education --Needs and Disbursements on (Box 7)
    - Nominating (Box 7)
    - Nursing and Nursing Education (Box 7)
    - Tuberculosis on (Box 7)
  - Commodore Hotel (Box 7)
  - Commonwealth Fund (Box 7)
  - Contracts and Lease (Box 7)
  - Coopeer, Dr. Henry S.F. (Box 7)
  - Co Tui (Box 7)
  - Cowdry, Dr. Edmund V. (Box 7)
  - Cowdry, Dr. Edmund V. (Board of Directors) (Box 7)
  - Crabtree, James A. (Box 7)
  - Curran, Jean Alonzo (Box 7)
  - Dtis, David (Box 7)
  - Deacon., J.B. (Box 7)
  - Decorations and Awards (Box 7)
  - Dewey, Thomas E. Jr. (Box 7)
  - Duvall, Jo, 1954-1964 (Box 7)
  - Duvall, Jo, 1964-1970 (Box 8)
  - E (Box 8)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration (Box 8)
  - Edison, Charles (Box 8)
  - Eloesser, Leo (Box 8)
  - Emergency Medical Service Training Schools, 1940 -1946 (Box 8)
  - Emergency Medical Service Training Schools - Robert Lim (Box 9)
  - Eason Eastern, Inc. (Box 9)
  - Exxon Corporation (Box 9)
  - Financial Reports:
    - China Office (Box 9)
    - General. Account Chungking Office (Box 9)
    - Directorate of Army Medical Service - Army Medical Admin. (Box 9)
    - Emergency Medical Service Training School (Box 9)
    - India Office (Box 9)
    - Kunming Office (Box 9)
    - National Health Administration – General (Box 9)
    - National Health Administration - Institution, etc. (Box 9)
  - Findley, Thomas (Box 9)
  - First National City Bank, 1962-1966 (Box 9)
  - First National City Bank, 1967-1970 (Box 9)
  - Fitch, Dr. and Mrs. George A. (Box 9)
  - Foley, Paul J. (Box 10)
  - Forkner, Claude (Box 10)
  - Form Letters, (2 Folders) (Box 10)
  - Former ABMAC Chapters (Box 10)
  - Foster, Charlotte H. (Box 10)
  - Estate of (Box 10)
  - Foundation Approaches (Box 10)
  - Franklin National Bank (Box 10)
  - Fulbright Acts (Box 10)
  - G (Box 10)
  - Gale, Hollis P. (Box 10)
  - Gelinas, Agnes (Box 10)
  - Grant, John B. (Box 10)
  - Green, Mrs. Edward H. (Box 10)
  - Greener, Roger S. (Box 10)
  - Gregersen, Magnus Jr, 1945-1970, (4 Folders) (Box 10)
  - Gregersen, Magnus I. - Expense account (Box 10)
  - Gregersen, Magnus I. - Nanking Training Course (Box 10)
  - Grieco, Michael H. (Box 10)
  - Group Research Program - Nanking, July 1948 (Box 10)
  - Guttmacher., Alan F. (Box 10)
  - H (Box 11)
  - Hallenbeck, Ernest A. (Box 11)
  - Hankemeyer, Natalie (Box 11)
  - Harrison, Mrs. Wilfrid (Box 11)
  - Hillman Foundation (Box 11)
  - History of ABMAC, (2 Folders) (Box 11)
  - Hodgman., Gertrude E., November 1950–1961, (2 Folders) (Box 11)
  - Hsu Su-En (Box 11)
  - Hu, Shih (Box 11)
  - Hume, Edward H. (Box 11)
  - Humphreys, George H., 1971-1976 (Box 11)
  - Humphreys, George H. - Trip to Taiwan (Box 11)
  - I (Box 12)
  - Incorporation Matters (Box 12)
  - Insurance (Box 12)
  - International Cooperation Administration (Formerly - Foreign Operation Admin.) (Box 12)
  - International Foundation, 1951-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 12)
  - International Red Cross (Box 12)
  - International Relief Committee (Box 12)
  - J (Box 12)
  - Japanese Peace Conference (Box 12)
  - Job Applications (no. 1 & 2), (2 Folders) (Box 12)
  - Job Applications (no. 3 & 4), (2 Folders) (Box 13)
  - Judd, Walter H. (Box 13)
  - K (Box 13)
  - Kiang, Chiping H.C. - Memorial Fund (Box 13)
  - Kight, Harry D. (Box 13)
  - Kight, Harry D. - Analysis of ABMAC (Box 13)
  - Klein, Julius and Saks (Box 14)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1941-1943, 1950-1968, (5 Folders) (Box 14)
  - Kohlberg, Jane Myers Memorial Fund Donor's List (Box 14)
  - Kohlberg, Jane Myers Residence Appeal (Box 14)
  - Lasker, Mrs. Albert D., (2 Folders) (Box 14)
  - Lau, Allen, 1964-1969 (Box 14)
  - Lau, Allen, 1970-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 15)
  - Lee, Ting D. (Box 15)
  - Levin, Maurice (Box 15)
  - Li, Mia C. (Box 15)
  - Lilly Mrs. Eli (Box 15)
  - Lim, Robert K. S. (Box 15)
  - Lin, Yutang L. (Box 15)
  - Lippincott J.B. Company (Box 15)
  - Liu, J. Heng, 1946 - June 1947, (2 Folders) (Box 15)
  - Liu J, Heng, July 1947 to December 1948, (5 Folders) (Box 16)
  - Liu, J. Heng, October 1950 to December 1951 (Box 16)
  - Liu, J. Heng, 1952-1959, (8 Folders) (Box 17)
  - Liu, J. Heng (Box 17)
  - Fellowship Correspondence (Box 17)
  - Lobenstine., Edwin C. (Box 17)
  - Lockwood, John S. (Box 17)
  - McBride, Robert (Box 18)
  - McClure, Robert (Box 18)
  - McKee, Fredetick C. (Box 18)
  - Macy, Josiah Jr. Foundation (Box 18)
  - Maffett, Minnie L. (Box 18)
  - Marx, Louis Foundation (Box 18)
  - Medical Colleges – General (Box 18)
  - Medical Conferences, (2 Folders) (Box 18)
  - Meleney, Clarence (Box 18)
  - Meleney, Frank L. (Box 18)
  - Meng, Chi (Box 18)
  - Merck & Co., Inc. (Box 18)
  - Microfilm Project (Box 18)
  - Mills, Emma DeLong (Box 18)
  - Ministry of Information - Republic of China (Box 18)
  - Mississippi State College for Women. Student Interfaith Association18 (Box 18)
  - Morris, Lawrence (Box 18)
  - N (Box 18)
  - Narration for Color Slides (Box 18)
  - National Central University College of Medicine - Chengtu and Nanking (Box 18)
  - National Chungshan University Medical College (Box 18)
  - National Committee (Box 18)
  - National Defense Medical Center, 1948-1971, (13 Folders) (Box 19)
  - National Defense Medical Center, 1972-1976, (5 Folders) (Box 20)
  - National Defense Medical Center - Nursing School (Box 20)
  - National Epidemic Prevention Bureau (Box 20)
  - F.Tang (Box 20)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1951-1968, (2 Folders) (Box 20)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs - Slide Set Correspondence (Box 20)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs - General (Box 20)
  - National Health Administration: (Box 21)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 21)
    - 1940-1941 King, P.Z. (Box 21)
    - 1942 (Box 21)
    - 1942-1943 King, P.Z. (Box 21)
    - 1944 King, P. Z. (Box 21)
    - 1945 King,, P.Z. (Box 21)
    - Yang,, Marion (Box 21)
  - National Health and Welfare Retirement Association (Box 21)
  - National Hsiang Ya Medical College (Box 21)
  - National Information Bureau (Box 21)
  - National Institute of Health (Box 21)
  - National Kweiyang Medical College (Box 22)
  - National Medical College of Shanghai (Box 22)
  - National Medical Colleges (Box 22)
  - National Northwest Hospital, Lanchow (Box 22)
  - National Peking University Medical School (Box 22)
  - National Red Cross. Society of China:
    - Foreign Auxiliary (Box 22)
    - General (Box 22)
    - Hu, William (Box 22)
    - Lim, Robert [2 Folders] (Box 22)
    - Rangoon Officer (Box 22)
  - National Red Cross Society of China - Reports (Box 23)
  - National Red Cross Society of China - Unit-Reports (Box 23)
  - National Red Cross Society of China - Wang, Chengting (Box 23)
  - National Red Cross Society of China - Wu, C.Y. (Box 23)
  - National Taiwan University (Box 23)
  - Needham, Joseph (Box 23)
  - New Life Movement (Box 23)
  - New York City Sales Tax Exemption Certificate (Box 23)
  - New York State Sales Tax Exemption Certificate (Box 23)
  - Norton, Paul L., 1950-1961, (2 Folders) (Box 23)
  - Norton, Paul L., 1964-1967 (Box 23)
  - Nurses Association of China (Box 23)
  - Nursing Committee (Box 23)
  - Nursing Schools (Box 23)
  - Ochsner, Alton, 1971 & 1972 (Box 24)
  - Ochsner, Alton [June 1971] - Trip to Taiwan (Box 24)
  - P (Box 24)
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. (Box 24)
  - Peace Corps Participation (Box 24)
  - Penicillin Information (Box 24)
  - Penicillin Project (Box 24)
  - Penney Memorial Church (Box 24)
  - Pew Memorial Fund (Box 24)
  - Philadelphia Diabetic Society (Box 24)
  - Pierson, Richard Jr. (Box 24)
  - Plasmoquin (Box 25)
  - Program (ABMAC), 1947 & 1948 (Box 25)
  - Protein Metabolism and Shock Study (Box 25)
  - Pyrogen Project (Box 25)
  - Q (Box 25)
  - R (Box 25)
  - Raine, Kendall A. Jr. (Box 25)
  - Ransom, Carter (Box 25)
  - Assistant Treasurer of ABMAC (Box 25)
  - Reader's Digest Audit (Box 25)
  - Reader's Digest Foundation (Box 25)
  - Ren, S.D. (Box 25)
  - Renesant Press, Inc. (Box 25)
  - Richmond County Medical Society (Box 25)
  - Women's Auxiliary (Box 25)
  - Robinson, Leland Rex (Box 25)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 25)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr. (Box 25)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr. Memorial (Box 25)
  - Root, Walter Stanton, (2 Folders) (Box 25)
  - Russell Sage College (Box 25)
  - S (Box 25)
  - Schenley Corporation (Fellowship) (Box 25)
  - School Health Program (Box 25)
  - Scudder, John (Box 26)
  - Scudder, John [Trip to China, 1945] (Box 26)
  - Severinghaus, Aura E., 1971-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 26)
  - Severinghaus, Elmer L. (Box 26)
  - Severinghaus, Leslie R. (Box 26)
  - Shanghai Anti-Tuberculosis Association (Box 26)
  - Shaw, Bruno (Box 26)
  - Shem, Van Alan (Box 26)
  - Smedley, Agnes (Box 26)
  - Smith, Carl A. (Box 26)
  - Smith, Harry P. (Box 26)
  - Smith, Paul C. (Board of Directors) (Box 26)
  - Soroptimist International Association, 1952 (Box 26)
  - Special Events (Box 26)
  - Starr, Charlotte C. (Box 26)
  - Steadman, Thomas E. (Box 27)
  - Stevens, Helen Kennedy [China Trip] (Box 27)
  - Sze, Szeming (Box 27)
  - T (Box 27)
  - Tai, T.Y. (Box 27)
  - Tamney, J.B.V. (Box 27)
  - Tenduf La, Peggy, 1951 (Box 27)
  - Tenth Birthday Celebration (Box 27)
  - Tillett, William [Board of Directors] (Box 27)
  - Tong, Hollington K. (Box 27)
  - Trimbey, Edward J., 1951-1967, (2 Folders) (Box 27)
  - Trimbey, Edward J., 1971 & 1972 (Box 27)
  - Tripp, John T. (Box 27)
  - Tsiang Tingfu - Chinese Delegate to U.N. (Box 27)
  - U (Box 27)
  - Underwriters Trust Company (Box 27)
  - United Board for Christian Colleges in China (Box 28)
  - United China Relief, Inc. (Box 28)
  - United China Relief, Inc.:
    - Chungking Committee of Coordination (Box 28)
    - Medical Conference, April 1942 (Box 28)
    - Medicine and Public Health in China (Box 28)
    - Post, John (Box 28)
    - Sweet, Lennig (1944-1945) (Box 28)
  - United Council for Civilian Relief on China. Inc. (Box 28)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (Box 28)
  - United Service to China, Inc.:
    - Committee on Coordination (1947) (Box 28)
    - Committee on Medicine and Health (Box 28)
    - Executive Committee (1948) (Box 28)
    - Financial Reports (Box 28)
    - B.A. Garside (Box 28)
    - General (Box 28)
    - Legal Consolidation (Box 28)
    - McNutt, Paul (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Meetings (Box 28)
  - Upjohn Company, (2 Folders) (Box 28)
  - V (Box 29)
  - Van Duke, Harry B. (Box 29)
  - Van Slyke, Donald D., (2 Folders) (Box 29)
  - Visiting Professor, 1967-1971, (2 Folders) (Box 29)
  - Visiting Professor - Correspondence with Medical Schools (Box 29)
  - Visscher, Maurice B. (Box 29)
  - W (Box 29)
  - Wang, An (Box 29)
  - Wang, C.H. (Box 29)
  - Waung, G.P. - ABMAC China Office (Box 29)
  - Webber, John W. (Box 29)
  - Webster, Jerome P., 1948-1961, (2 Folders) (Box 29)
  - Webster, Jerome P., 1971-1975 (Box 29)
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C. (Box 29)
  - Wei, Joseph C. (Box 29)
  - Welch, Bishop Herbert (Box 30)
  - Wellwood, Magarethe, (2 Folders) (Box 30)
  - Wergeland, Floyd L. (Box 30)
  - Whiteford, William K. (Box 30)
  - Whitlock, Emmet (Box 30)
  - Williams, Robert R. (Box 30)
  - Williams, Ruth (Box 30)
  - Wissman,W.W. (Box 30)
  - Wright, Adele Cohn (Box 30)
  - Wu, K. C. (Box 30)
  - Y (Box 30)
  - Yang, Wen-tah, (2 Folders) (Box 30)
  - Yen, Y. C. James (Box 30)
- Series III: Program Files
  - Aborigines Health Program (Box 31)
  - Allergy - Immunology Program (Box 31)
  - ABMAC:
    - 20th Anniversary News Release (Box 31)
    - 25th Anniversary (Box 31)
    - 25th Anniversary in New York, December 13, 1962 (Box 31)
    - 25th Anniversary in Taipei, October 29, 1962 (Box 31)
    - 30th Anniversary (Box 31)
    - 30th Anniversary S.S. Independence October 14, 1967 (Box 31)
  - ABMAC Fellows Club – Taiwan (Box 31)
  - ABMAC Health and Medical Committee, 1967 & 1968 (Box 31)
  - ABMAC Health and Medical Committee. 1st Meeting, U.N. March 13, 1968 (Box 31)
  - American Chinese Medical Society (Box 31)
  - Armstrong, George Ellis (Box 31)
  - Army Medical Service (Box 31)
  - Army Nursing School, 1946-1957 (Box 32)
  - Army Nursing School (Box 32)
  - Narration for color slides (Box 32)
  - Bowl of Rice Party (Box 32)
  - Brohel, Craige – Secretary (Box 32)
  - Bulletin Materials, (2 Folders) (Box 32)
  - Chinese Embassy (Box 32)
  - Chow, Mei-yu (Box 32)
  - Conference on the Organization of Medical Teaching Mission to China, 1949 (Box 32)
  - Family Planning Association of China, May 1954-December 1967, (3 Folders) (Box 33)
  - Final Drafts from Taiwan Tapes, 1967 (Box 33)
  - Garside, Bettis Alston (Box 33)
  - Gregersen, Magnus I. (Box 33)
  - Gregersen, Magnus I. – Project (Box 33)
  - Health and Medical Committee - Luncheon Meeting, (2 Folders) (Box 34)
  - Burma Shipments, India, 1945 (Box 34)
  - Joint Treatment Center (Box 34)
  - Judd, Walter H. (Box 34)
  - Lau, Allen, (2 Folders) (Box 34)
  - Lau, Allen:
    - Comments on Mr. Kight's Report (Box 34)
    - Congressional Record (Box 34)
    - Report to the Executive Committee (Box 34)
    - Speeches By (Box 34)
  - Lau, Allen Taiwan Trip: (Box 35)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 35)
    - 1966 - Correspondence (Box 35)
    - 1967 (Box 35)
    - 1968 - Tapes, Working Drafts (Box 35)
  - Lim, Robert K. S. (Box 35)
  - Liu, Chieh – Tribute (Box 35)
  - Loo, Chih-the, 1958-1969, (4 Folders) (Box 35)
  - Maternity and Child Health Project, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Medical Library List:
    - Basic Medical Library List, (2 Folders) (Box 35)
    - Extra Copies of Microfilm List (Box 35)
    - Nursing Books (Box 35)
    - Proceedings of National Academy of Science (Box 35)
    - Pyrogen Project Journals (Box 35)
    - School of Nursing Library, Lanchow, Kansu (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - National Defense Medical Center (Box 36)
  - National Defense Medical Center:
    - ABMAC Approach to FOA Funds (Box 36)
    - Peng, T.M. Deputy Director (Box 36)
    - Publications (Box 36)
    - Teaching Health Center (Box 36)
  - National Student Nurses Association (Box 36)
  - Nursing Committee - Minutes and Agenda (Box 36)
  - Overseas Chinese School (Box 36)
  - Peden, Katherine (Box 36)
  - Projects (Box 36)
  - Prosthetic Workshop, June 1966 (Box 36)
  - Research and Development Corporation of China (Box 36)
  - School of Health Program (Box 36)
  - Semi-Annual Report on Protein Metabolism Project, 3 April 1966 (Box 36)
  - Shu, Frank (Box 36)
  - Shyu, Kwai-Wang (Box 36)
  - True Light Centennial (Box 37)
  - U.S. Medical Mission, August 11-17, 1968 (Box 37)
  - Veterans Hospital (Box 37)
  - Yeh, Shu – Dormitory (Box 37)
  - Yen, C.K. - Vice President, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Yen, C. K. - Dinner, (2 Folders) (Box 37)
- Series IV: Alfred Kohlberg File
  - ABMAC - U.C.R. (Box 38)
  - Army Medical College (Box 38)
  - Army - Chinese (Box 38)
  - Chinese Red Cross (Box 38)
  - Correspondence (Box 38)
  - Emergency Medical Service Training School (Box 38)
  - India and Shipping (Box 38)
  - Interviews (Box 38)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, (3 Folders) (Box 38)
  - Kohlberg., Ida J. (Box 38)
  - Meeting (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous: Letters, Instructions, Reports (Box 38)
  - Originals (Box 38)
  - Originals and Mimeo Copies (Box 38)
  - Personal (Box 38)
  - Reports (Box 38)
- Series V: Development Files
  - ABMAC Village: (Box 39)
    - ABMAC House (Box 39)
    - ABMAC Village (Box 39)
    - ABMAC Village Community Plan, 1960 (Box 39)
    - Chennault Fund for Front Line Freedom Fighters (Box 39)
    - Kohlberg, Ida Kindergarten at NDMC (Box 39)
    - National Defense Medical Center Faculty Living Quarters Drive (Box 39)
    - Nursing Residence (Box 39)
    - PUMC Residence (Box 39)
    - Roosetelt Memorial Residence, ABMAC Village, NDMC, Taiwan (Box 39)
    - Taschen Fund Raising (Box 39)
  - Business and Professional Women's Club: (Box 40)
    - 1965-1966, (5 Folders) (Box 40)
    - Agreements Blueprint (Box 40)
    - Chinese Embassy Reception for BPWC Officers (Box 40)
    - Clubwomen's Life Magazine (Box 40)
  - Business and Professional Women's Club: (Box 41)
    - Daniels, Grace B. - Presentation (Box 41)
    - Maffett, Minnie L. (Box 41)
    - Peden, Katherine - Award (Box 41)
  - Commission on Medical Education (Box 41)
  - Foundations Related to ABMAC:
    - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals (Box 41)
    - China Foundation (Box 41)
    - Free China Fund (Box 41)
  - Fund Raising Projects:
    - Chinese Refugee Relief 1962 (Box 41)
    - Committee of One Million (Box 41)
    - Dependents Hospital Fund (Box 41)
    - Dooley, Tom Foundation (Box 41)
    - Hong Kong Training for the Blind (Box 41)
    - Meleney, Frank L. Fellowship Fund (Box 41)
    - Project Concern (Box 41)
    - Selected List of ABMAC Donors (Box 41)
    - So Others May Live Showings (Box 41)
  - Han Li-wu (Box 41)
  - Hankemeyer, Natalie - China Letter (Box 41)
  - Health Demonstration Centers (Box 41)
  - Hu Shih (Box 41)
  - Libraries (Severinghaus) (Box 41)
  - Lim, Robert K. S. (Box 41)
  - Lists (Box 41)